Guide to the Yale Poetry Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale poetry collection
1822-1926
RU 377
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
The materials consist of poems written by Yale students.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 47 (YRG 47), Collections documenting teaching and learning in Yale academic programs.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of poems written by Yale students.
Poems; Yale College (1718-1887) -- Students; Yale University -- Poetry; Yale University -- Students
- Yale poetry collection, circa 1822-1926; Accession 19ND-A-386
  - Poetry submitted for A. S. Cook Poetry Prize, unidentified, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Poetry submitted for A. S. Cook Poetry Prize, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Poetry submitted for A. S. Cook Poetry Prize, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bowen, George Y. 1822: "They talk of love and pleasure…" (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Peet, Harvey P. Y.1822: "Alike the busy…" (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Watterman, Thomas J. Y.1822: "The censure of ignorance…" (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Unknown: "Hans Breilman gif a party…" copied by Prof. Bache, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Anketell, John H. Y.1855: "We are parting…" (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mallery, Garrick (1784-1866) Y. 1808: Book of Poetry, 1842-1850 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mallery, Garrick (1831-1894) Y. 1850: Book of Poetry, 1846-1894 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Crane, Oliver Y.1845: "To My Wife", 1896 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - McLaughlin [Edward] Thompkins Y.1833: Poetry, 1883-1884 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Porter, Edward Clark Y.1858: Notebook of Poetry, 1855-1869 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Saunderson, H. H. Valedictory Poem and Summer Poem (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Browning, Phillip Y. Class of 1889: Poems, 1930s (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Anonymous: Poem for the Class of 1828 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Patterson, Thomas Cleveland: Class of 1927 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Baird, Cyrus. Non-graduate of the Class of 1912: "Sense and Non-Sense" (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Poetry of John Addison Porter, circa 1841-1861; Accession 1985-A-077
  - Poetry of John Addison Porter, circa 1841-1861 (Box 1)